Wei Shi

Mobile: 021-833136

Email: shiwe790@yahoo.com

#### **Personal Profile**

I am an energetic, self-motivated, hardworking QA engineer with broad work experience in both business and IT industries. My primary aim is to develop my technical skills and become a well-rounded engineer and valuable member of the engineering community.

#### **Relevant skills**

- Experience with website, application and API testing.
- Good Knowledge with Amazon web Service (AWS). Adobe Experience Management (AEM) system, Adobe Analytics, Saas applications, SEO, Firebase, Google Analytics. Google Search Console, Google Play Console, Apple App connect, Testflight, CDP, Adswizz.
- Great knowledge with Jira, Confluence. Zephyr Scale, Bamboo, Github. Charles Proxy, Postman, BrowserStack, Appium, Samsung PLM, Samsung automation testing tools and Network RF testing tools.
- Excellent with Microsoft applications including Excel, Word PowerPoint, and Outlook.
- Experience with Agile methodologies.
- Strong desire for quality and attention to detail.
- Excellent verbal and written communication skills.
- Strong time management and organizational skills and great team player.
- Completed ISTQB foundation level training.
- Completed the Project Management Executive Education Short Course at the University of Auckland (2019).

# **Employment History**

❖ Digital Test Analyst

Mediaworks NZ, Auckland

Mar. 2022- Present

Key Tasks:

Execute testing procedures during software build and release process to ensure it
meets established quality standards for the radio websites ( the Edge, The Rock,
MaiFM, GeorgeFM, TheSound, Magic, The Breeze, MoreFM), the mobile application
(rova), and API.

- Test the implementation of new features and functionality for the radio websites and the mobile application, and API.
- Configure and maintain test environments.
- Investigate defects in order to determine the potential cause for failed tests.
- Document and report test results according to the required procedures.
- Create and maintain test cases for changes in functionality, workflow and integrated systems.
- Manage app release activity in Google play store and iOS app center.
- Prepare release notes and manage web release activities.
- Work with PM, BA, developers, UX designers, content editors and stakeholders on application defects and enhancements to ensure proper escalation and follow up.

# ❖ Test Analyst

Enrolmy, Mt Eden

Mar. 2023 — present (Part-time)

- Design, develop and execute test plans and test cases.
- Perform API testing.
- Diagnose, track and manage quality issues to resolution.
- Collaborate with developers to identify, understand and resolve the root cause of defects.

# \* Technical Engineer

Samsung NZ, Northcote

Mar. 2014 — Mar.2022

Key tasks:

- Perform sanity testing, functional testing and regression testing pre and post code releases, during various stages of the SDLC process.
- Perform RF test/ drive test including voice calls, SMS, video calls and mobile data over operator's GSM, UMTS, LTE and 5G network.
- Review the functional & non-functional requirements, test plans, test cases & ensure the solution is tested to the core business and IT demands.
- Liaise with Samsung RnD to troubleshoot, identify and resolve issues by providing an analyzing various application logs.
- Use automation tools to conduct tests such as stress tests and smoke tests on Samsung's pre installed applications.

- Maintain and improve automation by writing the automation test script.
- Project Owner for Samsung's Wearable, Wi-Fi tablet and IoT's model launches in NZ market.
   Prepare reports and documents for SDOC (Supplier Declaration of conformity) to meet the required New Zealand standards
- Manage the planning, scheduling and resource allocation of FTR projects.
- Involve in lab inventory and sim cards management
- Take a lead role in the development and growth of the team by mentoring and training new team members
- Provide technical support for products marketing and sales activities
- Member of the Samsung NZ Health and Safety committee

## **Education**

- Master of Engineering Studies, Electrical and Computer Engineering (ECE),
   The University of Auckland, Auckland, Feb.2012 Nov.2012
- Graduate Diploma, Electrical and Computer Engineering (ECE),
   The University of Auckland, Auckland, Feb.2011 Nov.2011
- Bachelor of Science, Electronics/Mathematics.
   The University of Otago, Dunedin, Feb.2005 -Nov.2007

## Referee:

Will provide upon request.